A Finding Aid to the Holger Cahill Papers, 1910-1993, bulk 1910-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.cahiholg
Archives of American Art
- Works Progress Administration Federal Art Project, 1934-1970; Series 3; (Boxes 2-14, 18, MMs009; 10.75 linear ft.)
  - Photographs, circa 1935-1948; 3.14
    - Arizona Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1109, Frame 1232-1251)
    - Arizona Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5297, Frame 0486-0554)
    - California Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1109, Frame 1252-1337)
    - California Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5297, Frame 0556-0741)
      (includes photos of Benianino Bufano, Donal Hord and John Palo-Kangas)
    - Colorado Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1109, Frame 1338-1354)
    - Colorado Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5297, Frame 0743-0760)
    - Connecticut Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5297, Frame 0762-0763)
    - District of Columbia Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0406-0428)
    - District of Columbia Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5297, Frame 0765-0787)
    - Florida Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0001-0079)
    - Florida Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5297, Frame 0789-0919)
    - Idaho, Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5297, Frame 0921-0930)
    - Illinois Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0080-0161)
    - Illinois, Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5297, Frame 0932-1268)
      (includes photographs of Edward Millman and Mitchell Siporin)
    - Indiana Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5297, Frame 1270)
    - Iowa Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 3) (Reel 1110, Frame 0162-0163)
    - Iowa Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 3) (Reel 5297, Frame 1272-1344)
    - Iowa Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (3 of 3) (Reel 5298, Frame 0005-0023)
    - Kansas Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5298, Frame 0025-0033)
    - Louisiana Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5298, Frame 0035-0042)
    - Maine Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5298, Frame 44)
    - Maryland Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1110, Frame 0164-0165)
    - Massachusetts Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0166-0236)
    - Massachusetts Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5298, Frame 0046-0189)
    - Michigan Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0237-0284)
    - Michigan Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5298, Frame 0191-0234)
      (includes photos of Samuel Cashwan and Walt Speck)
    - Minnesota Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0285-0289)
    - Minnesota Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5298, Frame 0236-0339)
      (includes photo of Gov. Harold E. Stassen)
    - Mississippi Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0290-0301)
    - Mississippi Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5298, Frame 0341-0354)
    - Missouri Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5298, Frame 0356-0357)
    - Montana Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5298, Frame 0359-0378)
    - New Mexico Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0302-0311)
    - New Mexico Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5298, Frame 0380-0497)
      (includes photo of Patrocino Barela)
    - New York Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 3) (Reel 1110, Frame 0454-0647)
    - New York Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 3) (Reel 5298, Frame 0499-1357)
      (includes photos of Arshile Gorky, Edward Laning, Eric Mose and James Michael Newell)
    - New York Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (3 of 3) (Reel 5299, Frame 0004-0360)
    - North Carolina Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0312-0327)
    - North Carolina Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0362-0596)
      (includes photo of Ambassador Josephus Daniels and Robert Vose)
    - Ohio Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 328)
    - Ohio Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0598-0625)
    - Oklahoma Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0329-0338)
    - Oklahoma Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0627-0670)
    - Oregon Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0339-0346)
    - Oregon Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0672-0779)
      (includes photo of Louis Bunce)
    - Pennsylvania Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0347-0350)
    - Pennsylvania Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0781-0819)
    - Rhode Island Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0351-0356)
    - Rhode Island Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0821-0830)
    - South Carolina Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5299, Frame 0832-0833)
    - Tennessee Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5299, Frame 0835-0842)
    - Utah Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0357-0366)
    - Utah Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0844-0887)
    - Virginia Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0367-0405)
    - Virginia Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0889-0946)
    - Washington Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0429-0433)
      (includes photo of Eleanor Roosevelt, 1938)
    - Washington Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 0948-1001)
    - Washington Photographs? (state not identified), circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1110, Frame 0434-0435)
    - West Virginia Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5299, Frame 1003-1022)
    - Wisconsin Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0436-0449)
    - Wisconsin Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 1024-1062)
    - Wyoming Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1110, Frame 0450-0453)
    - Wyoming Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5299, Frame 1064-1082)
    - Unidentified Locations Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1110, Frame 0648-0677)
    - Miscellaneous Center Projects and Artwork Photographs, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 5299, Frame 1084-1125)
      (includes photo of Reuben Nakian)
- Writings, Lectures and Speeches, 1916-1960; Series 4; (Boxes 14-15, 18; 1.0 linear ft.)
  This series contains typescripts of writings, lectures and speeches by Cahill and others. A large portion of the material relates to the WPA FAP, but there are also book and exhibition reviews and other works of art criticism by Cahill. For additional copies of writings by Cahill see Series 8: Printed Material.
  The series is arranged into five subseries:
  4.1: Lectures and Speeches by Cahill, 1930-1945
  4.2: Lectures and Speeches by Others, 1916-1940
  4.3: Writings by Cahill, 1928-1960
  4.4: Writings by Others, 1932-1957
  4.5: Typescripts for Art For The Millions, 1936-1940
  - Lectures and Speeches by Cahill, 1930-1945; 4.1
    This subseries contains typescripts of lectures and speeches by Cahill, many with hand-written notes and copies of drafts. Parts of some typescripts are missing. Material is arranged chronologically with undated material placed first.
    - [ Ernest Peixotto], undated; (lecture notes) (Reel 5290, Frame 1020-1022)
    - WPA Lecture, Chicago, undated; (lecture notes) (Reel 5290, Frame 1023-1025)
    - [ American Folk Art], Phillips Memorial Gallery, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 1026-1066)
    - [ History of Support of American Art], undated (Reel 5290, Frame 1067-1085)
    - [ Government Support of Art], Radio Talk, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 1086-1094)
    - Independents, Society of Independent Artists, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 1095-1110)
    - [ Development of Visual Training Aids], U.S. Navy Training Aids Development Center, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 1111-1124)
    - [ Crafts as Art], New Hampshire Talk, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 1125-1144)
    - American Folk Art, Radio Talk, [November 1930] (Reel 5290, Frame 1145-1154)
    - American Folk Sculpture, Newark Museum, 1931 (Reel 5290, Frame 1155-1168)
    - New Horizons, Chicago, [1936] (Reel 5290, Frame 1169-1197)
    - [ Women's Role in Art], Women's Democratic Club, May 24, 1936 (Reel 5290, Frame 1198-1209)
    - Speech for Southern Women's National Democratic Organization, New York, December 1936 (Reel 1105, Frame 0319-0329)
    - [ Old and New Paths in American Design], Newark Museum, November 6, 1936 (Reel 5290, Frame 1210-1250)
    - Art for the Few or the Many?, American Association of University Women, November 15, 1936 (Reel 5290, Frame 1252-1271)
    - Untitled, FAP, 1937 (Reel 1105, Frame 0330-0332)
    - [ Index of American Design], St. Louis, Missouri, January 31, 1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 1272-1286)
    - [ WPA-FAP], Metropolitan Museum of Art, March 28, 1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 1287-1332)
    - [ Aims and Achievements of the WPA-FAP], American Artists Congress, December 18, 1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 1333-1355)
    - Child Art, April [1938] (Reel 5290, Frame 1356-1362)
    - Goodyear Dinner speech, 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 1363-1371)
    - New Jersey Art at the World's Fair, Newark Museum Radio Talk, February 11, 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 1372-1378)
    - Dedication of Murals for WNYC Radio Studios, August 2, 1939; (lecture notes) (Reel 5290, Frame 1379-1381)
    - Untitled, FAP, circa 1940; (1 of 2) (Reel 1105, Frame 0293-0302)
    - Untitled, FAP, circa 1940; (2 of 2) (Reel 1105, Frame 0305-0318)
    - Project Control Talk, circa 1940 (Reel 1105, Frame 0303-0304)
    - What Is Tradition?, Artists' Congress, 1940 (Reel 5290, Frame 1382-1402)
    - North Carolina Speech, April 1, 1940 (Reel 5290, Frame 1403-1441)
    - Untitled, FAP, 1941 (Reel 1105, Frame 0333-0346)
    - [ Contemporary American Art and Its Antecedents], Cosmopolitan Club, [1941] (Reel 5290, Frame 1442-1489)
    - [ Support for Artists vs. Museums], American Federation of Arts, [1941] (Reel 5290, Frame 1490-1493)
    - [ American Art History], American Institute of Decorators, 1941 (Reel 5290, Frame 1494-1541)
    - Art in the National Defense, Radio Talk, January 27, 1941 (Reel 5290, Frame 1542-1545)
    - The Face of America, Cosmopolitan Club, February 10, 1941 (Reel 5290, Frame 1546-1549)
    - The Face of America, Cosmopolitan Club, cont., February 10, 1941 (Reel 5291, Frame 0005-0041)
    - [ Role of Art in the Community], People's Art Center Association, May 5, 1941 (Reel 5291, Frame 0042-0078)
    - Art in Wartime, December 3, 1941 (Reel 5291, Frame 0079-0081)
    - [ Use of Art in War], Dartmouth College, January 15, 1942 (Reel 5291, Frame 0082-0098)
    - [ American Attraction to Art of the Far East], 1944 (Reel 5291, Frame 0099-0106)
    - [ U. S. Government Art Projects, 1945] (Reel 5291, Frame 0107-0130)
  - Lectures and Speeches by Others, 1916-1940; 4.2
    This subseries contains typescripts of lectures and speeches by others, often with notes and copies of drafts. The majority of the material relates to the WPA FAP. Records are arranged chronologically with undated material placed first.
    - Pigmentation or Chemistry of Artists' Colors by K. R. Leipold, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0133-0140)
    - History of Painting by Henry H. McLellan, Jr., undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0141-0147)
    - [ Launching of California Supervisors] by Thomas C. Parker, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0148-0157)
    - An Edinburgh Address on Design and Industry by Frank Pick, October 1916 (Reel 5291, Frame 0158-0174)
    - Museum Service to the Art Industries by Richard F. Bach, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1927 (Reel 5291, Frame 0175-0186)
    - Exhibition of American Folk Art at the Albright Art Gallery, Radio Talk by Nora Christensen, June 20, 1932 (Reel 5291, Frame 0187-0198)
    - Public Works of Art Project by Edward Bruce, Advisory Committee to the Treasury on Fine Arts, January 17, 1934 (Reel 5291, Frame 0199-0204)
    - The New Day in Negro Art by Harry H. Sutton, Jr., Bethune-Cookman College, Daytona Beach, Florida, January 17, 1937 (Reel 5291, Frame 0205-0207)
    - The Negro in the Field of Painting and Sculpture by Harry H. Sutton, Jr., January 28, 1937 (Reel 5291, Frame 0208-0212)
    - Mellon's Art by Maury Maverick, U. S. House of Representatives, March 1, 1937 (Reel 5291, Frame 0213-0217)
    - Community Art Centers by Thomas C. Parker, May 4, 1937 (Reel 5291, Frame 0218-0227)
    - [ Federal Art Project] by Thomas C. Parker, May 22, 1937 (Reel 5291, Frame 0228-0257)
    - Opportunities for the Negro in American Art by Harry H. Sutton, Jr., Davis Street School, Jacksonville, November 2, 1937 (Reel 5291, Frame 0258-0260)
    - The Highlights in Negro Art by Harry H. Sutton, Jr., Davis Street School, Jacksonville, February 9, 1938 (Reel 5291, Frame 0261-0265)
    - The Opportunities of the Negro in Art by Harry H. Sutton, Jr., Davis Street School, Jacksonville, February 14, 1938 (Reel 5291, Frame 0266-0269)
    - Federal Sponsored Community Art Centers by Thomas C. Parker, American Library Association, June 14, 1938 (Reel 5291, Frame 0270-0291)
    - What Is the American Way? by Harry L. Hopkins, July 16, 1938 (Reel 5291, Frame 0292-0306)
    - [ Negro Art] by Thomas C. Parker, Tuskegee Institute, July 29, 1938 (Reel 5291, Frame 0307-0320)
    - Extension Remarks on Addresses in Honor of American Artists Who Have Decorated Federal Buildings by Elbert D. Thomas, U. S. Senate, April 25, 1940 (Reel 5291, Frame 0321-0327)
    - Speech Before the Second National Conference on Handicrafts, Penland, North Carolina by Whitney Atchley, September 3, 1940 (Reel 5291, Frame 0328-0336)
  - Writings by Cahill, 1928-1960; 4.3
    This subseries contains typescripts of writings by Cahill, including book and exhibition reviews. A substantial portion of the material found here was written during Cahill's directorship of the FAP. Material is arranged chronologically with undated material placed first.
    - American Resources in the Arts, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0340-0395)
    - The Government in Art, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0396-0400)
    - Request for Opinions of FAP Program, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0401-0404)
    - Index of American Design: What It Is, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0405-0409)
    - [ Index of American Design], undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0410-0429)
    - The Stations of the Cross of San Gabriel Mission, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0430-0436)
    - [ Americans' Interest in Art], undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0437-0450)
    - [ Orientation Toward Living American Art], undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0451-0463)
    - Art in Democracy, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0464-0470)
    - Russia and the United States, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0471-0477)
    - The Icelandic Discovery of America, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0478-0485)
    - History of American Art Proposal, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0486-0491)
    - Concepts of Folk Art, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0492-0496)
    - American Folk Art, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0497-0505)
    - Folk Art, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0506-0682)
    - Puritan Imagination, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0683-0697)
    - [ Development of Modern American Art], undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0698-0702)
    - Description of American Art in a Portfolio, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0703-0719)
    - Industrial Design and Education, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0720-0725)
    - The New Literacy, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0726-0734)
    - Prefatory Note, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0735-0736)
    - Community Art Centers in the Western States, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0737-0741)
    - From Furniture to Politics, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0742-0744)
    - Exhibit of Steigel Glass at the National Museum, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 0745-0749)
    - Review of Library of Congress Exhibition, [ Creative Art of the American Negro], undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1107-1113)
    - Exhibition Review, Ancient Arts of the Andes, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1114-1123)
    - Article Review, on Photography for Art in America by Kirstein, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1124-1128)
    - Book Review, Divided We Fought: A Pictorial History of the Civil War, 1861-1865 by David Donald, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1129-1133)
    - Book Review, The Meeting of the East and West by F.S.C. Northrop, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1134-1146)
    - Book Review, The Son of the Gamblin' Man by Mari Sandoz, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1147-1157)
    - Book Review, [ The Place of the Picture as Historical Document] by Mr. Taft, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1158-1164)
    - Industrial Art, 1928 (Reel 5291, Frame 0750-0765)
    - [ William Zorach, 1932] (Reel 5291, Frame 0766-0795)
    - Art of the Common Man, [1933] (Reel 5291, Frame 0796-0813)
    - Art For Whom? A Survey of Present-Day Conditions in the Arts, [1935] (Reel 5291, Frame 0814-0820)
    - [ Federal Art Project, 1936] (Reel 5291, Frame 0821-0823)
    - The Federal Art Project, [1937] (Reel 5291, Frame 0824-0838)
    - The Art Program, [1937] (Reel 5291, Frame 0839-0841)
    - [ WPA Arts Program, 1937] (Reel 5291, Frame 0842-0852)
    - Federal Art Project, 1939 (Reel 5291, Frame 0853-0858)
    - Honors Won by WPA Artists, 1936-1941 (Reel 5291, Frame 0859-0880)
    - [ Views on Modern Art in Time of War, 1942] (Reel 5291, Frame 0881-0885)
    - Note on the Employment of Artists in War Time, [1942] (Reel 5291, Frame 0886-0888)
    - [ Publication of the Index of American Design, 1942] (Reel 5291, Frame 0889-0893)
    - [ Work of the WPA, 1944] (Reel 5291, Frame 0894-0896)
    - [ Art As an Ingredient of National Unity], 1944 (Reel 5291, Frame 0897-0916)
    - President Roosevelt and the U.S. Government Art Projects, [1945] (Reel 5291, Frame 0917-0944)
    - After Forty Years, American Federation of Arts, [1949] (Reel 5291, Frame 0945-0964)
    - Folk Art and the American Style (for House Beautiful), 1950 (Reel 5291, Frame 0965-0993)
    - Homage to Morgan Russell, [1953] (Reel 5291, Frame 0994-1009)
    - Paris Catalog, 1955 (Reel 5291, Frame 1010-1056)
    - Article for Marg Magazine on American Art in This Century, 1956 (Reel 5291, Frame 1057-1105)
    - Book Review, George Caleb Bingham: River Portraitist by John Francis McDermott, 1959 (Reel 5291, Frame 1165-1168)
    - Book Review, But Not for Love by Maynatalie Tabak, 1960 (Reel 5291, Frame 1169-1171)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments of Typescripts, 1938-circa 1942 (Reel 5291, Frame 1172-1223)
  - Writings by Others, 1932-1957; 4.4
    This subseries contains typsecripts of writings by others, many of which were produced as part of the WPA FAP. Material is arranged chronologically with undated material placed first.
    - Artists Union by Unidentified Author, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1227-1229)
    - Dr. Samuel Butler by Unidentified Author, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1230-1231)
    - To Paint and Stain Glass and Porcelain by Unidentified Author, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1232-1234)
    - Memorandum on a Post-War Reorganization of the Section of Fine Arts and Other Federal Projects by George Biddle, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1235-1244)
    - Early Cowboy Art by E. J. Bird, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1245-1248)
    - American Artists' Congress by Stuart Davis, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1261-1264)
    - Jose Delores Lopez [by Meredith Hare], undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1265-1271)
    - An Architect's Point of View by William Lescaze, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1272-1274)
    - Art Comes to the People by Eugene Ludins, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1275-1284)
    - The Artists' Union by Stevens Maxey, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1285-1287)
    - America As Americans See It by Henry McBride, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1288-1289)
    - The Development of American Mural Painting by Geoffrey Norman, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1290-1298)
    - Easel Painting by Harley Perkins, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1299-1301)
    - Art and Social Therapy by Frances Pollak, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1302-1306)
    - A New Attitude on Art by Walter Quirt, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1307-1310)
    - Some American Primitives by Elsa Rogo, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1311-1320)
    - An Introduction to the Living World of Art by Lincoln Rothschild, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1321-1323)
    - The Revival of Mosaic by Arthur W. Sears, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1324-1330)
    - The Third Dimension Progresses: The Diorama Project by George T. Senseney, undated; (includes photo of Senseney) (Reel 5291, Frame 1331-1342)
    - The Art of the Poster by George Melville Smith, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1343-1345)
    - Description of Sommer's Working Methods by William Sommer, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1346-1348)
    - Pottery Methods by Walter Speck, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1349-1354)
    - [ Widening of the Sculptor's Field] by Emmanuel Viviano, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1355-1359)
    - Poems by Max Weber, undated (Reel 5291, Frame 1360-1365)
    - Editors' Information from [ America As America Sees It] by Henry McBride, 1932 (Reel 5291, Frame 1391-1394)
    - Zoar by Nixon of the Society of Separatists of Zoar, 1933 (Reel 5291, Frame 1366-1383)
    - Simonson Article by [John Cotton Dana, 1935] (Reel 5291, Frame 1384-1390)
    - Ancient and Renaissant Rome by Morgan Russell, 1935 (Reel 5291, Frame 1395-1404)
    - Artists' Coordination Committee by Frederic Knight, [1936] (Reel 5291, Frame 1405-1412)
    - Index of American Design by Ruth Reeves, 1936 (Reel 5291, Frame 1413-1416)
    - Art and the State v. America by Lewis Mumford, 1936 (Reel 5291, Frame 1417-1425)
    - [ Art Classes for Young People] by Samuel Friedman, 1936 (Reel 5291, Frame 1426-1430)
    - [ Sunday Night Forums] by Dorothy Paris, [1936] (Reel 5291, Frame 1431-1440)
    - Derivation and History of Weathervanes by Richard Farmer Smith, [1937] (Reel 5291, Frame 1441-1443)
    - Tobacconists Figures, Research Notes Compiled by WPA Program, 1937 (Reel 5291, Frame 1444-1475)
    - WPA Art Project Murals by Sheldon Cheney, 1938 (Reel 5291, Frame 1249-1257)
    - A Long Term Program for the National Handicraft Association, Based on Reports Collected During the Summer of 1938 by Humphrey J. Emery (Reel 5291, Frame 1476-1486)
    - The WPA Federal Art Project, Its Contribution to the American People by Fanny Bowles Vanderkooi, 1940 (Reel 5291, Frame 1487-1492)
    - Urban Recreational Planning by Caroline C. Williams, [1941] (Reel 5291, Frame 1493-1515)
    - Those Who Support the Art Center by H. A. Zurbrick, 1941 (Reel 5292, Frame 0004-0006)
    - [ John Cotton Dana] by M.D.C. Crawford, circa 1944 (Reel 5291, Frame 1258-1260)
    - [Review of Cahill's Book Look South to the Polar Star] by Unidentified Author, 1947 (Reel 5292, Frame 0007-0010)
    - An American Renaissance and "The Pauper's Oath" by Helen C. Farrell, 1957 (Reel 5292, Frame 0011-0078)
  - Typescripts For Art For The Millions, 1936-1940; 4.5
    This subseries comprises typescripts by forty-eight of Cahill's colleagues discussing various media and philosphies of the visual arts used for the book Art For The Millions: Essays from the 1930s by Artists and Administrators of the WPA Federal Art Project, edited by Francis V. O'Connor (Boston: New York Graphic Society, 1973). Typescripts are arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Table of Contents (see also sol Box 18), circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0082-0093)
    - Abbott, Berenice, Changing New York, circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0094-0097)
    - Brown, Douglas, Subject Matter in Painting, circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0098-0100)
    - Brown, Samuel J., About Myself, circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0101-0103)
    - Cashwan, Samuel, The Sculptor's Point of View, circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0104-0107)
    - Clements, Grace, Organizing the Subconscious, circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0108-0114)
    - Curtis, Philip C., The Phoenix Art Center, circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0115-0119)
    - Davis, Stuart, The Social Education of the Artist, circa 1937 (Reel 5292, Frame 0120-0125)
    - Davis, Stuart, Abstract Painting Today, 1940 (Reel 5292, Frame 0127-0135)